# Sinthushan Sooriyakumar

Toronto ON., 1503 Midland Ave. M1P 0A1 Phone: 416-278-0956 | Email: sInthushan@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/sinthushan-sooriyakumar-58368a22/ | Github: https://github.com/sinthushan

## **SUMMARY**

Innovation analyst at TD Waterhouse with a bachelor's degree in Commerce from the University of Toronto and technical experience with experience in Python, Pandas, Visualization, and SQL from the University of Toronto's Fintech Bootcamp. I have a strong interest in turning raw data into an understandable and visually appealing form. With the technical skills from the Bootcamp and business acumen gained from my work experience, I have a strong set of skills that can be used in any environment.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, VBA, JavaScript

Tools: Git, AWS Sagemaker, S3, Lex, Excel, Alteryx, Flask, Dash

Databases: Postgres, SQLite

# **EXPERIENCE**

**TD Securities** Toronto, ON **Analyst** Nov 2021 - Current

Responsible in updating and maintaining Python codebase of several reconciliation pipelines to ensure team is meeting audit requirements.

 Writing ad hoc Python scripts to pull information and/or generate reports for executive level management.

**TD Wealth** Toronto, ON

## Innovation Analyst [Business Innovation team]

Sept 2019 - Nov 2021

Responsible for leading innovation and change management within business group

- Successfully pivoted teams to new portfolio management system for high net worth clients by creating training material and holding training sessions. Going through existing processes and amending them to wok on the new system. Creating new scripts to replace automation that the teams have grown accustom to in previous system
- Streamlined validation process of broker instructions lowering need for seasonal workers for RIF/RSP team

**TD Wealth** Toronto, ON

#### Analyst [Managed Accounts team]

July 2018 - Sept 2019

Ensuring trades processed are processed in a portfolio management system without error and reflected in our book of records as well as guaranteeing fees are appropriately charged and allocated correctly among the business.

Scaled up Fee recalculation process for cornerstone by automating data scraping and calculation to do multiple months at the same time

**TD Wealth** Toronto, ON **April 2017 – July 2018** 

#### Lead Wealth Operations Officer [Equities Team]

Automated existing process to reduce risk, increase efficiency and save on use of paper

- Improved efficiency by merging function of Equities, and Fixed Income teams
- Reduced risk and increased efficiency of account opening process during sudden spike in account openings save the need to hire 14 temp workers

• Gained recognition for time and money saved by winning the annual start award being the very few individuals to obtain the reward within their first year of employment.

## **PROJECTS**

### Japanese Yen Forecast | https://github.com/sinthushan/JapanesesYenForecast

- Testing ARMA, ARIMA, GARCH and Linear Regression model's ability to predict the value of the Japanese Yen relative to CAD to create a model for investors can use for speculation.
- The GARCH model was able to do better than the ARIM and ARMA both of which had a P-Value less than 0.05. Linear Regression model proved promising with out of sample RMSE being less than in sample.
- Utilized statsmodels.api library in python for ARMA, ARIMA and GARCH analysis and sklearn library to do the linear regression

## Classification Comparison https://github.com/sinthushan/ClassificationComparison

- Determining if different resampling methods (Naïve random oversampling, SMOTE oversampling, undersampling, and SMOTEENN) can beat a simple logistic regression when categorizing house loan for probable delinquency. Result can then be applied to a loan approval process.
- Resampled data using imblearn library in Python to apply oversampling/undersampling methods and to imbalanced classification report to compare metrics such as precision, recall and accuracy to determine winning model
- SMOTE method seemed to be the clear winner

## Robo Advisor using AWS Lex | https://github.com/sinthushan/unit13-challenge

- Robo advisor that offers a simple portfolio based on answers given.
- Robo advisor was able to determine the amount of information given in the initial request and determine what follow up questions were necessary
- Utilized the AWS Lex for language processing and Python in the backend to perform validations and construct portfolio

## **EDUCATION**

# **University of Toronto School of Continuing Studies**

Toronto, ON

Fintech bootcamp

24-week bootcamp covering topics such as Pandas, SQL, machine learning, AWS, Algorithmic trading, and blockchain.

**University of Toronto Mississauga** 

Mississauga, ON

Bachelor of Commerce Specialist in Finance